I worked at the CIA. It's a big
lumbering bureaucracy with a lot of
stupid people. And it's it's not like it
is in the James Bond movies where
everybody's like, "Wow, right on top of
their game." No, there are a lot of
dopes.
>> Let me just show you this and I was want
to get your uh your response to it. So,
this is Jenker from a place I used to
work, TYT. And here's what he says about
>> like in the old days, man, they they
could do some
>> So he's interviewing a guy, I think, who
has written a book on the CIA and watch
this. So in the old days, he says,
>> who's [clears throat]
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Now I believe we have the opposite
problem. They're not evil enough.
[laughter]
>> He's talking about the CIA that they're
they used to really be bad guys, but now
they're not evil enough. Let's listen.
>> They're like not doing anything, right?
But are they risking their lives to
infiltrate? I mean, no. We never
infiltrated al Qaeda. No. Yeah. I mean,
that's unbelievable to me, right?
>> A little bit.
>> Uh, not only did we infiltrate al Qaeda,
we invented al Qaeda and now al Qaeda is
being welcomed. They did our dirty work
in Syria. We paid them and now they're
doing they're welcomed by the Secretary
of State and the former head of the CIA
in the United States in front of
roomfuls of dignitaries. So, what uh
Well, I'll play a little bit more and
then I'll get your response. We We never
even infiltrated al-Qaeda. We invented
them anyway.
>> Why would we have to do that? Why would
we have to implement
>> China invading Taiwan?
>> Yeah.
>> Embarrassing for our intelligence
community.
>> No, they don't want to. They don't.
>> So this whoever this genius is says it's
embarrassing for our intelligence
community that they didn't infiltrate al
it's a real interview. This really
happened
>> want to go through that risk. That's
that's my assessment. They're willing to
take some risk but not risk their lives.
But that's that's the CIA. That's you're
supposed to do that and hopefully in the
service of US citizens. In
>> fact, a lot of people you'd meet that
>> Oh my god. That's Barry Eisler.
>> Is that who that who's that? Tell me who
that is. Barry Eler is a former CIA
officer. I interviewed Barry this
morning. Uh Barry's a former CIA officer
uh who went on to be a prolific and very
successful author of uh espionage
fiction.
>> Well, that is sounds like fiction what
he's saying right there to Jenkuger that
uh it was embarrassing that this
intelligence community did not
infiltrate al-Qaeda. [laughter]
Do so you you obviously don't agree with
that assessment, right?
>> No. Yeah, I I disagree with you slightly
and and I'll explain why. Um I don't
think we invented al-Qaeda. I think we
foolishly made a decision once al-Qaeda
became the organization it became. It it
partially morphed from the mujaheden.
>> Yes.
>> But um and we armed them.
>> So we armed the musha which which
morphed into the al-Qaeda.
>> Yeah.
>> And as Hillary Clinton said, we created
them. She said that in congressional
testimony.
>> Pretty much.
>> Yeah. Um,
I think we were directly responsible for
the for the creation of ISIS, but that
that's a separate issue. But we
foolishly believed that we could then
we could then manipulate al-Qaeda to the
point where we could get, for example,
the 9/11 hijackers who had already
arrived in the United States to turn
against what we called al-Qaeda um uh
base al-Qaeda uh the the leadership
Osama bin Laden, Iman Zawahi, Muhammad
at
>> he was the number the number three the
military I think is he was a mere for
military affairs or some stupid title
like that. Um, it was naive. It resulted
in the deaths of 3,000 Americans in one
day, plus 2 million Muslims and another
8,000 soldiers after that.
>> Yeah, it was just it was stupidity.
>> Okay.
>> Stupidity.
>> Um,
>> but let me add one other thing. Checker
I'm sorry, Czech Wigger's an idiot.
>> He's always been an idiot.
>> Have you heard his position on Sex with
Horses yet?
>> [laughter]
>> Well, listen, you're asking a Greek to
comment on a Turk, so already I'm I'm on
a thin line here, [laughter]
but um but he's so arrogant that he
wants us to believe that when the CIA
makes a decision to do something or the
CIA takes a policy position, the first
thing they have to do is they have to
call Chank Wiger and explain what
they're doing. It's like, that's not the
way espionage works, you
So, [laughter]
so I just um
well, let me show you this. Let me show
you this. Hang on. There's I have so
much here to tell you. [clears throat]
>> So, here's what Scott Ritter says. Let
me introduce you to the Special Activity
Center. The CIA may be incompetent that
I grant you, but to say they don't carry
out covert action designed to undermine
overthrow the governments of sovereign
states is a whole new level of stupid.
The CIA is the greatest threat to global
stability in the world. No other single
organization is involved in the
violation of law, including our own,
more than the CIA. America and the world
would be far better and safer place
without the CIA. Doug, do you have
anything to say about Scott Ritter's
assessment of that?
>> I I agree with every word of that.
>> Okay, great question. Scott Ritter Oh,
yeah, I know him well. Uh-huh. Scott
Ritter.
>> So, the idea that that the CIA doesn't
overthrow That's crazy, right?
>> It's crazy. It's it's like it's it's
task number one is to overthrow
government. They've been doing it since
the Italian election of 1949.
>> Let me
>> He came in and said Scott Ritter and he
was talking about how the inner agency
didn't want to hear the truth about
weapons of mass destruction in Iraq.
What's the inner agency? Cuz I don't
think they're incompetent. I think they
compartmentalize. You're allowed to look
at what you're allowed to look at much
like everybody here in America now. And
nobody can see. I talked to people that
have end and they don't know about
things that have been disclosed already
such as MK Monarch which I thought they
would never disclose. We had a guest on
who sent us the link in 2024
NSA archives.
>> I wrote a paper by name.
>> Yeah. By name.
>> Yeah. So
>> MK Chick Who is the inner agency? Who is
that?
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. Um
>> where do I even begin? I'll give you
I'll give you I'll answer. That's your
monarch.
>> I'll answer your question by telling you
um by telling you a story. Uh
when I got back from Pakistan, I was I
was promoted on the on the strength of
the Abu Zubeda capture, which I'm now
ashamed of because the man was utterly
innocent of any of any crime against the
United States. And I've consistently
called for his release from Guantanamo.
He's been there he's been in our custody
for 23 and a half years now. Never been
charged with a crime. But anyway, um I
got promoted when I got back and I was
named the executive assistant to the
CIA's deputy director for operations. In
that position, you you see literally
everything that the CIA is doing around
the world. You have to sign I had to
sign a half a dozen new uh security
agreements just to start work on my very
first day.
So, we were getting ready to attack Iraq
and a cable came in that was not just
sensitive. It was from one of these
special compartments, but it was
actionable. Like, I needed to I needed
to act on it now. Well, it came in a
minute before my morning briefing of the
deputy director and all the associate
deputy directors. So I went up to the
office and I said,"Well, we have to
start the briefing today with an
incredible cable that just came in in
the such and such compartment." And the
deputy director says, "Stop."
He says, "You and I are the only people
in the room cleared for this
information." Which the room included
the associate deputy director for
operations, the associate deputy
director for policy planning, the
associate deputy director for counter
intelligence, the associate deputy
director for counter counterterrorism.
It's like, are you kidding me? So
there's a smaller group than this little
group
and there was. So he said, "I'll take
the cable. I'll brief the director." So
I just handed it to him and everybody
was kind of doing this like pretending
that they hadn't heard any of this.
>> I was shocked. And then I I when
everybody finished their their everybody
just says what they're working on that
day, um afterwards he said, "Close
call." I said, "I just assumed that if
you're one of the top eight leaders of
the CIA, you're cleared to know what the
CIA is doing." And he said, "Yeah, it's
kind of funny, couldn't you?"
>> That's amazing. That's I wonder. So, um,
let me play one more video in this vein
talking about the ridiculous things that
people think believe about the CIA
today. Let's listen. There was a time in
America where the state department uh
would carry the Pentagon would
orchestrate and carry out coups in you
know Latin American countries for
instance or in Iran like there was a
time when the government engaged in all
sorts of unsavory
schemes across the globe. That's
definitely true. Okay,
that's not the government we have today.
How does anyone look at the inc? Like
honestly, I don't think the current
federal government is even competent
enough to carry out a coup. I mean, they
tried multiple times in Venezuela and
failed. Failed.
And like the way like the
some of the MAGA Republicans quite
honestly talk about the federal
government makes me think, oh my god,
they're asleep at the wheel. They don't
understand just how incompetent the
federal government is. They can't get
anything straight. They can't get
anything straight. And you guys think
that they're like they're wiretapping
you and they're scheming and they're
planning on throwing Tucker Carlson in
prison for talking to Vladimir Putin?
Really?
>> Yeah. Come on.
>> I mean, like, look, man, I interviewed
the CIA agent long time ago, about now
nearly 10 years ago. It was a really
amazing interview. She told me about
honeypot uh schemes and stuff and how
they trick their [clears throat] targets
into
>> thinking that they're going to get a
sexual relationship. Like, it was
amazing, very candid interview. And
she's like, "Look, what this whole thing
and that deep state stuff on the right
wing hadn't started yet." She's like,
"The number one problem with the CIA is
they've become bureaucrats." And
>> so I don't I just would like to get a
CIA officer's response to that kind of
ridiculous.
>> It hurts my brain. It really does. I
mean, listen, you can even go on
Wikipedia
and they'll give you a laundry list of
of all the regime change operations that
the CIA is known to have been involved
in. What makes these guys think that the
CIA is not at least as dangerous as it
always has been? I it's it's a mystery
to me.
>> Edward Snowden revealed that they're
that they're tapping everyone. Joshua
Schulty. They didn't give Joshua
Schultey 40 years for nothing because he
talked about nothing because he talked
about exactly what it is that the CIA is
out there doing around the world,
including in the United States.
>> And look what they're doing to Julian.
This was at the time they're prosecuting
Julian Assange. They're saying like
this. They're like, "Are you kidding
me?"
>> You are exactly right.
>> They got his they got his toilet uh
bugged.
>> Literally.
>> Yes.
>> Literally. They bugged the toilet. And
they didn't just walk in and do it. They
got the Spanish intelligence service to
hire this company and the company was
working with the Israelis and the
Israelis were working with the Brits and
>> come on a lot of moving parts.
>> A lot of moving parts. Okay. Um
what? Wait, hang on, Kurt. I can't Why
Why can't I hear him?
>> Go ahead, Kurt. What?
>> Okay. The deep state and I can't repeat
this enough. Peter Dale Scott, a
Berkeley leftist professor.
>> Yes.
>> Is the guy who invented the term deep
state after he studied it for 50 years.
It's not a right-wing thing. It came
from a leftist Berkeley professor who
also talked about COG, which none of
these people talk about continuity of
government. In fact, I'd like to know
from John, how much of this stuff do
they do under COG? Because Ali North
hearings are talking about it. The
shooting of Trump uh when everybody was
lambasting that Kimberly, what's her
name? She's from COG, the head of Secret
Service when Trump got shot the first
time.
>> How much of this is like COG stuff? And
do they keep it away from the CIA that
way or
>> Yeah, that's a great question.
>> Oddly enough, the CIA has nothing to do
with COG. They keep the CIA out, which
is smart because you don't want the CIA
to be leading the country in the event
of a disaster, especially when you're
going to have to question whether the
CIA had something to do with the
disaster, right? But yeah, continuity of
government is is probably priority
number one, which is which is one of the
reasons why COG came out into the news
this week because literally everybody I
don't know that this has ever happened,
at least not in my lifetime. Literally
everybody in the constitutional line of
succession went to the Charlie Kirk uh
memorial service.
>> Oh,
>> literally everybody. What would have
happened if a nuclear device had gone
off in that stadium? Literally, the
entire
government would have been wiped out.
So, we would have been ruled by what? A
military huna,
>> the guy from the Department of Energy or
something.
>> Yeah.
>> Right.
>> From Denver. That's what's under the
airport. The new capital.
>> Exactly. And there's one in West
Virginia at Mount Weather. Yes.
>> What is underneath the airport in
Denver?
>> The new capital for COG in case of a
nuclear war. the you know the the uh Dr.
Strange Love underground thing where
they all sit around. That's what's in
Denver. That's why
>> there's one in Denver and there's one on
the Virginia West Virginia border called
Mount Weather. It's a hollowed out
mountain
>> and that's where that's where the
designated few are supposed to be taken
in the event of a nuclear conflict.
>> No kidding.
>> They had a congressional picnic in 2012
when the solar flare almost hit us and
they would have went in there and left
you to fry.
>> You know, they gave us a tour when I
first joined the CIA. They gave us a
tour of Mount Weather. I actually never
believed Mount Weather existed. And then
they took us inside and I was like,
"You've got to be kidding me." So, this
is real. And they were like, "Yeah, it's
real."
>> And and they're very specific about who
gets to go. It's much smaller than you
might imagine. So, it's
>> I imagine it's very small.
>> It's very small. the president, the vice
president, secretaries of state,
defense, the national security adviser,
a couple of the very top congressional
leaders, the majority leader, minority
leader, the speaker of the house, and
their families, their immediate
families, and then that's it.
>> Well, what do you say? What do you say
about Katherine Austin Fitz when she
says that they've been they've somehow
stolen 20 trillion dollars from the
federal government and they building the
building these underground cities to
sustain the elite? Have you heard her
talk about that?
>> Yeah, I've heard her say that. I don't
think that's true. First of all, I just
don't think people are that smart.
[laughter] I I really don't I worked at
the CIA. It's a big lumbering
bureaucracy with a lot of stupid people.
And it's it's not like it is in the
James Bond movies where everybody's
like, "Wow, right on top of their game."
No, there are a lot of dopes. I I was
just telling a friend of mine yesterday,
um we were getting ready to go on uh
this is the honest to God's truth. We're
ready getting ready to go on a raid in
in Pakistan. We're going to raid an
al-Qaeda safe house. And I remember
saying, "Where's where's Chris?" "Oh,
uh, Chris couldn't come." What do you
mean he couldn't come? That's why he's
here. No, it turned out Chris beat his
wife. So, uh, we have this rule. If you
get caught beating your wife, you can't
carry a gun. So, he can't go on the raid
without a gun. I said, "Okay, where's
Jimmy?" "No, Jimmy got psychoaced."
Psychologically evacuated. I said,
"Why?" He went nuts this morning. Like,
all right. All right. Let's just let's
just go with what we have. So, it's not
like the James Bond movies. Everybody's
either nuts or stupid or slow or they
have been in headquarters for 10 years
because they're cowards and they're
afraid to go overseas and it's easier to
get promoted at headquarters. It's not
like what people think that it's this,
you know, tip of the spear and we're
going to go in, we're going to kill the
president and we're going to name our
guy the new president. Come on. Well,
what I think is it's like in Tragedy and
Hope by Carol Quigley. Circles within
circles. That's what an inner agency
would be. So, of course, you're going to
have a thick layer of stupid
bureaucrats.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. But somebody knows what they're
doing. It's not no one steering it. And
the reason those underground bases exist
was because of nuclear war. That's the
Edward Teller days.
>> That's why [clears throat] they built
that
>> Exactly. It's not like we just thought
of it. Now, the missing 20 million or 20
trillion rather. I I heard it was more
like 4 trillion. But it's not that it's
missing, it's that it's been spent or
wasted. Um, a lot of it in secret
programs, so there's no paperwork to
document it. People have retired or died
and forgotten. And Price Waterhouse
Coopers goes in to the Pentagon to try
to find it. And then three years later
they throw up their hands and they say
we cannot figure out this accounting
system and they just quit.
>> I thought it was Elon's fault for Doge
not
>> No, they they were able to find 250
billion which everybody laughed at. Like
where's Then where's the other 3.75
trillion that we can't find?
>> But they were able to um
I mean we did a Demidon coup. So they
they pulled that See how he pulled that
off.
>> Exactly. Right. They got finally got it
took them 25 years, but they got rid of
Assad.
>> That's right.
>> That's another one.
>> And they've had they did it through
their proxies, right?
>> Libya.
>> Uh they did Libya, right? Uh they did
get rid of Maduro in a short time and
now they're back trying to do it again.
>> Yes.
>> Um and I'm sure they're doing stuff like
that all over the place
>> and they're not going to advertise it to
us.
>> That's right. Like Nepal just happened
and I'm like I wonder if that is organic
or if they went in and gave people money
cuz that's what they do, right? the the
Yeah,
>> I think it don't succeed unless you got
the bad feelings there though, right?
It's not like they could just make it
happen out of thin air. It could happen
when you see the time is right for it to
happen.
>> That's right.
>> Come see me on tour. I'll be in
Sacramento, San Francisco, Irvine,
California, Sydney, Melbourne, in
Brisbane, Australia, and then Burbank,
California the day after Thanksgiving.
Go to jimmy.com for a link for tickets.
[music]